# Christopher Allison

### **RF Engineering Technician - Vulcan Wireless**

Ramona, CA

-Email me on Indeed: http://www.indeed.com/r/Christopher-Allison/0e1e519fb0bbb41f

Highly motivated individual looking for a Lead RF Engineering position. Can work with minimal supervision and in stressful situations. Test and tune RF circuits up to X band. Full system testing and setup. Excellent soldering skills (J-STD-001 trainer with space addendum). Can diagnose down to the component level. 8 years experience in this industry. Board bring up and and test data record documentation experience. Secret clearance. Management experience in a laboratory environment.

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

# Work Experience

#### RF Engineering Technician/ Lab Manager

Vulcan Wireless - San Diego, CA March 2013 to Present

Component Assembly for prototypes as small as 0201

- Performed modifications to flight units
- Performed Solder Inspections
- Environmental Tester Vacuum Chamber, Temperature Chamber and Vibration
- Tuned RF Circuits using Smith and Log Magnitude charts
- Processed RMA products
- Wrote technical documentation for end users
- Proficient in Or Cad, PADS, MS Office and PSpice
- BOM component selector for MPN's

## 12N Heavy Construction Equipment Operator

United States Army Sargent June 2007 to June 2011

15 month deployment to Iraq

- Air assault qualified
- 2 Army accommodation medals
- Warrior leadership medal
- 2 time solider of the month

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Excellent solder skills, circuit failure debugger, determine necessary modifications needed for circuit performance, tune and test RF circuits, test and measure RF performance, proficient in using lab test equipment- Oscilloscope, Network Analyzer, Spectrum Analyzer, Signal Generators, Power Meters, Digital Multi-Meters, Vector Signal Analyzer.

# Education

# **Bachelor's in Electrical Engineering**

ITT Technical Institute-National City - San Diego, CA 2012 to 2015

#### Skills

- Microwave
- PCB
- Antenna
- Microwave
- PCB
- Radio
- Radio Frequency
- Surface Mount Technology
- Military
- System Testing
- Calibration
- Laboratory Management
- CAD
- IPC 610
- Laboratory Experience
- Soldering
- Schematics
- Research & development
- Manufacturing

# Military Service

#### **Branch: Us army**

Service Country: United States

Rank: SGT 2007 to 2011

# Certifications and Licenses

#### **Secret Clearance**